Guide to the Bob Brown Oral History Project 2005-2010
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Interview with John Mercer, 2 April 2010; OH 396-065; Sound Recording, digital, 451 MB, Wav; Transcript, 30 leaves
  Mercer, a former Montana state legislator and Speaker of the Montana House, describes his early experiences in the Montana House and fellow legislators including Dave Brown, Francis Bardanouve, Jack Ramirez, John Vincent, Hal Harper, Bob Thoft, John Harp, Fred Thomas and Fred Van Valkenburg. He talks about his leadership philosophy as Speaker and the role of the Republicans in the Montana Legislature during the 1990s. He also discusses governors Ted Schwinden, Marc Racicot, Stan Stephens, Judy Martz, and Brian Schweitzer.
- Interview with John Vincent, 22 April 2010; OH 396-066; Sound Recording, digital, 506 MB, Wav; Transcript, 30 leaves
  Vincent, a former Montana state legislator and Speaker of the House, describes his interest in political science and how that influenced him to run for public office. He discusses his leadership roles in the Montana House of Representatives and Speaker of the House, Minority Leader, and Majority Whip. He talks about members of the House as well as Montana governors Stan Stephens, Ted Schwinden and Brian Schweitzer.
- Interview with Alec Hansen, 15 April 2010; OH 396-067; Sound Recording, digital, 496 MB, Wav; Transcript, 35 leaves
  Hansen, a lobbyist for the Montana League of Cities and Towns, reminisces about growing up in Butte, Montana, during the 1940s and 1950s. Hansen discusses working for Montana Governor Forrest Anderson, describing the governor’s work style and vision for Montana state politics.
- Interview with Bruce Crippen, 27 May 2010; OH 396-068; Sound Recording, digital, 461 MB, Wav; Transcript, 32 leaves
  Crippen, a former Montana state senator, talks about his twenty years of service as a Montana state senator. He describes working with Montana governors Stan Stephens, Marc Racicot and Judy Martz. He also discusses his involvement in Marc Racicot’s gubernatorial campaign.
- Interview with Elin G. Parks, 4 September 2010; OH 396-069; Sound Recording, digital, 215 MB, Wav; Transcript, 24 leaves
  Elin G. Parks, a former professional dancer and model, talks about her grandfather, former U. S. Senator Thomas Walsh. She discusses his career and the details surrounding his death. She also talks about her life as the wife of a naval officer and Mobile Oil employee.
- Interview with John T. Hoag, September 2010; OH 396-070; Sound Recording, digital, 232 MB, Wav; Transcript, 15 leaves
  Hoag talks about living on Lake McDonald in Glacier National Park. He reminisces about spending time with two Montana senators, Tom Walsh and Burton K. Wheeler, and their families.
- Interview with John Cobb, 29 September 2010; OH 396-071; Sound Recording, digital, 723 MB, Wav; Transcript, 81 leaves
  Cobb, a former Montana state representative, discusses his introduction to politics and why he decided to run for the Montana State Legislature. He describes his years in the legislature and fellow legislators including Bob Marks, Chuck Swysgood, Leo Giaocometta, and John Mercer. He also talks about the different governors he served under including Judy Martz, Marc Racicot, and Stan Stephens. He finishes with speculation on the future on the Republican Party, the Tea Party and the Montana State Legislature.